<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-30T19:46:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aviv’s Crazy Flight</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Date Auction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/28/the-date-auction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Date Auction" /><published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/28/the-date-auction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/07/28/the-date-auction.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents</h1>
<ol>
  <li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a>
    <ol>
      <li><a href="#explanation1">Explanation of First and Second Price Auctions</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<h1 id="introduction-">Introduction <a name="introduction"></a></h1>

<p>Disclaimer: I don’t take any responsibility for the conversation that comes up 
when you start talking about this with your significant other. :P</p>

<p>Once upon a time there were a pair of people and they were destined to meet and 
live a beautiful life together. There was only one snag… The way they met was 
through a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charity_dating#:~:text=Charity%20dating%20is%20a%20process,value%20in%20such%20a%20date.">dating auction</a>. The dating auction is a 
strange sort of auction because of the fact that there may be a soft “reserve price”
that is independent of the selling price. A simple example of how this could end
badly is where the bidder of the hypothetical pair wins the auction for 3 dollars.
The auctioned partner is so offended that, although they went on the date, there
was no happily ever after. The bidder, although actually having quite a high 
valuation of the auctioned partner might not have bid high because he understood
the probability was very low anybody else would win the auction when he bid anything
over 3 dollars. Clearly there is an incentive for the bidder to not only take into
account his own probability of winning in his consideration but also how the object
of the bid feels about the winning bid as well.</p>

<p>I will go into a bit of math a bit later… Needless to say this pair desperately
needs a strategy!</p>

<p>To begin thinking about this we should dive into two different kinds of auctions
that appear in many introductions on the topic.</p>

<ol>
  <li>First Price Auction</li>
  <li>Second Price Auction</li>
</ol>

<p>There are many many others and an infinite variation on these two alone but 
let’s go into a tiny bit of detail. We will show soon how the dating auction, 
even when using a second price mechanism approaches a first price revenue.</p>

<h2 id="to-explain-the-two-basic-auctions">To Explain the Two Basic Auctions<a name="explanation1"></a></h2>

<p>A first price auction is your standard auction where there are a bunch of people
in a room screaming and the auctioneer listens for the highest bid(actually this
is an english auction but very similar) and at the end of the auction when the 
auctioneer decides the game has been played sells the item for the price that 
was shouted.</p>

<p>A second price auction is also a standard auction but less widely known to 
lay-people. It is a variation where instead of paying the price that you shouted 
for the item, you pay the price of the second highest bidder’s bid. 
You may ask “Why is this even a thing?” The answer to that when you pay the 
second highest bid it becomes in your favor to bid exactly how much you value the
item.</p>

<p>Let’s do some math:</p>

<p>Let $ \beta^I(x) $ and $ \beta^{II}(x) $ be the strategy for a first and second
price bidder respectively where x is the value the bidder actually places on the
object. Let $ f(x) $ be the probability distribution function that the bidder 
places a value x on the object. 
<br /></p>

\[F(x) = \int_0^x{f(y)dy}\]

<p><br />
F(x) is also known as the cumulative distribution function. That is F(x) represents the statement
“What is the probability that a bidder places a value x or less on an item?” 
Another quantity of interest for second price auction would be $ F_2(x) $. 
This $ F_2(x) $ could be read as “What is the probability that the second highest
bidder has a value x or less?” 
We can write this as a function of F(x) by realizing that saying “What is the 
probability that the second highest bidder has a value x or less?” is the same
as saying “What is the probability that one bidder has a bidder higher than x
and the rest lower than x?”</p>

\[F_2(x) = (1-F(x))F(x)^{N-1}\]

<p>Each bidder will want to maximize his returns. His returns are simply the difference
in how much the bidder pays and how much he percieves he receives.</p>

\[\mu(x) =  \begin{cases} 
                        x-\beta(x),&amp; \text{if win}\\
                        0 &amp; \text{otherwise}
                        \end{cases}\]

<p>This is saying that if the bidder loses then nothing is lost. If he wins then he
gets the object but loses his bid.</p>]]></content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Table of Contents Introduction Explanation of First and Second Price Auctions]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome To Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome To Jekyll" /><published>2016-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/20/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>To add new posts, simply add a file in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory that follows the convention <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext</code> and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>GitHub User</name><email>your-email@domain.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry></feed>